Guide to the Leland Spencer papers, ca. 1916-1992.
Spencer, Leland papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Leland Spencer papers, ca. 1916-1992.
21-10-908
Leland, Spencer 1896-
52 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Printed Materials, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter concerning economic aspects of pricing and distribution of milk, especially in New York and New Jersey.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Marketing, Cornell University, milk marketing consultant.
Cornell University Class of 1918, Ph.D. 1923
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter concerning economic aspects of pricing and distribution of milk, especially in New York and New Jersey; courses at Cornell; extension work, and activities as an economic analyst and consultant for state and federal agencies, as well as farmer and dealer organizations in the milk industry; correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, financial statements, and publicity material of the New York State Bureau of Milk Publicity (1934-1942) and Milk for Health, Inc. (1949-1958) and its successor, the Producers Milk Market Development Board (1958-1960); and printed matter, reports, and correspondence concerning his testimony in the "Safeway Case" regarding milk prices in California. Also, correspondence and printed matter of Dean William I. Myers as member of the New York State Governor's Special Committee on Milk Licensing; and notebooks of laws, rules, regulations, and sample forms used by the New York State Dept. of Agriculture and Markets.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Spencer, Leland,1896-; Benson, Walt.; Myers, William Irving, 1891-1976.; Milk for Health (Organization); New York (State).Bureau of Milk Publicity.; New York (State).Dept. of Agriculture and Markets.; Producers Milk Market Development Board.; Safeway Stores, Inc.
Subjects:
Dairy laws.; Milk--Quality.; Milk yield.; Milk trade.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Includes collections 21-10-726 and 21-10-1200.
CONTAINER LIST
- New York Market, 1930-1957 (Box 17)
- Dairymen's League, 1917-1930s (Box 17)
- Northeast Dairy Region (Box 17)
- New York Market, 1944-1977 (Box 18)
- Dairylea, 1980s (Box 18)
- New York Milkshed, 1937-1957 (Box 19)
- New York Milkshed (continued), 1937-1957 (Box 20)
- Production Milk Prices, 1965-1969 (Box 20)
- Production Milk Prices (continued), 1958-1967 (Box 21)
- Federal Order, 1964-1965 (Box 21)
- Personal Publications, 1933-1965 (Box 21)
- Spencer Writings, 1945-1957 (Box 22)
- Spencer Writings, 1958 - 1970 (Box 23)
- Class Handouts, 1936-1958 (Box 23)
- Sanitary Control, 1959-1968 (Box 24)
- Market Structure, Competition and Regulation, 1939-1968 (Box 24)
- Federal Milk Order, 1967-1979 (Box 25)
- Articles: International Milk; Low Fat Milk; Sterile Milk; Evaporated Milk; Concentrated Milk; Canned Whole Milk, 1952-1956 (Box 26)
- Articles (continued): Bibliography; Agricultural Economics Resolutions; Milk Reorders; Home Delivery, 1916 - 1977 (Box 27)
- Class Handouts, 1960-1967 (Box 28)
- Dairylea - New York, New Jersey Orders, 1977 - 1978 (Box 28)
- Agricultural Economics Bulletins - Written by Spencer, 1962-1967 (Box 28)
- Dairylea - New York, New Jersey Orders, 1950-1968 (Box 29)
- Spencer Writings, 1924-1944 (Box 30)
- Dairylea - New York, New Jersey Orders, 1918-1930 (Box 31)
- Articles: Milk Bottles and Containers, etc., 1966-1968 (Box 31)
- International Milk, 1967-1969 (Box 31)
- Articles: Milk Orders and Containers, 1938 - 1953 (Box 32)
- Imitation Milk - Filler Milk, Cheese, Cottage Cheese, Butter, 1968 (Box 32)
- Milk Consumption and Production, 1967-1979 (Box 33)
- Federal Milk Order, 1941-1978 (Box 34)
- Cooperative Association; Producer Prices, 1954-1965 (Box 35)
- Federal Milk Order Pricing, 1954-1964 (Box 36)
- Farm Retail Price Specials, 1957-1965 (Box 37)
- U.S. Food Marketing Commission, 1940-1964 (Box 37)
- Milk Distribution Costs, 1936-1954 (Box 37)
- Milk Distribution Costs, 1955 (Box 38)
- Selling and Delivery Costs, 1945-1950 (Box 38)
- Dairy Management and Equipment, 1954-1960 (Box 38)
- Milk Consumption, 1924-1958 (Box 38)
- Market Structure; Drivers Wages/Labor Contract; Transportation/Freight Rates; Milk Handling from Farms, 1948-1974 (Box 39)
- Market Structure; Competition and Regulation, 1959-1965 (Box 40)
- Regional Cooperatives; Marketing System; Channels of Trade; School Milk, 1940s-1965 (Box 41)
- International Articles; Imports and Exports; Patronage Dividends, 1940-1992 (Box 42)
- Dairy Manufacturing Costs; Special Cost Studies; Data for Selected Markets; Publications, 1932-1979 (Box 43)
- Milk Control Board Investigation (1933-1934); New York-New Jersey Milk Study (1942-1948); Sales Data – (Borden and Sheffield); Company working papers (Borden’s and Dellwood); Publicity material, 1933-1948 (Box 44)
- New York/New Jersey Metropolitan Milk Distribution Study (1944); Complete set of forms used, list of branches and routes, milk costs, payroll data (Much of the information pertains to Borden and Sheffield); Milk Standardization Study (1947-1948); Robert Moseley- National Research Council Committee (1948), 1944-1948 (Box 45)
- Milk Industry in Germany (1949); British Milk Study (1952-1953); Central Milk Plants in Italy (1954) – Spencer and Gabriele Gaetani, 1949-1954 (Box 46)
- Sheffield -financial data and cost studies (1940s); Events pertaining to milk delivery (1941-1944); New York Marketing Agreement (1933); Proposed Federal License–New York/New Jersey (1934-1935); Four States Conference on the New York Milk Problem (1936), 1934-1944 (Box 47)
- Early Developments–Committee of Eighteen (1933-1934); Legal Cases; Prices;Laws and Court Cases (1933-1989) (Box 48)
- Orders (1933-1964); Reports (1933-1946); Butter (before 1940); Oleomargarine (1933-1971); Mercantile Exchanges–Future Trading (1928-1969), 1928-1971 (Box 49)
- Dried Whole Milk (1944-1992); Non-fat Dry Milk (1933-1968); Milk Compensation and Tests (1950s); Federal and State Standards (1953-1968); Frozen Desserts (1973-1982); Ice Cream and Frozen Desserts (before 1950 and later); Mellorine–imitation ice cream (1952-1962); Chocolate (1980s); Whey (1982-1992); Fermented Dairy Products; Sour Cream (1980s); Yogurt (1970s); Dairy policy issues (1979); Dairy Programs and Legislation (1967); Dairy Price Support Program (1968-), 1933-1992 (Box 50)
- Dairy Policies (1979-1991); Milk Marketing Orders (1970s-1980s); Antitrust (1980s); Milk Assembly (1934-1972); Vending Machines (1950s); Distribution (1938-1980); Milk Plants (1953-1978), 1934-1991 (Box 51)
- Butter prices (1953-1961); Litigation (1933-1988); Milk Dealers' Association of Metropolitan New York-Membership Letters (1947-1968), policies and correspondence (1970s); Advisory Committee on Milk Supply Response Study (1960s) (Box 52)